<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Severall proposals for the generall good of the Common-wealth. With the grounds and reasons thereof. Seriously propounded out of a reall desire of a firm establishment of the peace and liberties of the Common-wealth.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1651</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 36 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 9 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A92999</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S2800</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E624_7</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R206442</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99865604</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99865604</idno>
            <idno type="VID">117850</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A92999)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 117850)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 96:E624[7])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Severall proposals for the generall good of the Common-wealth. With the grounds and reasons thereof. Seriously propounded out of a reall desire of a firm establishment of the peace and liberties of the Common-wealth.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 14 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Stephen Daguall, bookseller at Alsbury,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1651.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Annotations on Thomason copy: "feb. 19. 1650."; the last two numbers of the imprint date have been marked through.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Fairfax, Thomas Fairfax, --  Baron, 1612-1671 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Courts --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1649-1660 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Commonwealth and Protectorate, 1649-1660 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-07</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-07</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:117850:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>SEVERALL PROPOSALS FOR THE GENERALL GOOD OF THE COMMON-WEALTH. WITH The <hi>Grounds</hi> and <hi>Reaſons</hi> thereof.</p>
            <p>Seriouſly propounded out of a reall deſire of a firm eſtabliſhment of the peace and Liberties of the <hi>Common-wealth.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON:</hi> Printed for <hi>Stephen Dagnall,</hi> Bookſeller at <hi>Alsbury.</hi> 1651.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:117850:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:117850:2"/>
            <head>Severall <hi>Propoſals</hi> for the generall good of the Common-wealth. With the <hi>Grounds</hi> and <hi>Reaſons</hi> thereof.</head>
            <p n="1">1. THat, for the more orderly proceeding in all caſes of Law, the Courts of Judicature may be continued ſtill at <hi>Weſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minſter</hi> (or ſo many of them, as upon ſerious examination ſhall be judged neceſſary) with ſuch Offices thereon de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pending, as ſhall be found apparently uſefull, and not burthenſome to the Common-wealth; And that the <hi>Termes</hi> may be kept at certain times of the yeer, and not according to the former moveable Feaſts, whereby the ſuperſtitious obſervation of thoſe Feaſts may be for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gotten; and the people the better attend their ſeaſons, and imploy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments in the Countrey; And that the ſeverall <hi>Termes</hi> may be made equall in length, whereby they may be the fitter for the diſpatch of all buſineſs relating unto each <hi>Term;</hi> For ſhould the Courts of Judi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cature, and the <hi>Terms</hi> now kept at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> be diſcontinued there, and ſetled in ſeverall Counties, or Provinces, many inconveniences would inevitably follow. As firſt there muſt be as many Offices erect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in each County, or Province, as neceſſarily depend upon all the Courts at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> all which muſt either be maintained by the State, or by particular perſons, whoſe Suits ſhall be depending there. 2ly, The ſeverall Judges of thoſe Provinciall, or County Courts, ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving no ſociety together, will cauſe a great alteration in the Laws, by their various Interpretations of them; which would bring ſo great a confuſion with it, that no perſon could either ſafely travell, or traffick in another Juriſdiction as being ignorant of the Laws, and Cuſtoms there in uſe. 3ly, The Courts in the ſeverall Provinces, or Counties being of equall power, there could be no Appeals in caſe of any unjuſt proceedings; or admit a Court ſhould be ſet up in any place, for Appeals, the oppreſſion would be very great, by reaſon of the multitude of Appeals, and the great charge all parties would be put unto in the proſecution, and defence of them, the whole buſineſs being to be heard again, with all the witneſſes therein. 4ly, The con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinuall reſidence of the Judges of each Province, or County, amongſt their kindred, and acquaintance, would often tempt them unto par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiality.
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:117850:3"/>5ly, Not onely the Cities of <hi>London,</hi> and <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> and parts adjacent would be impoveriſhed for want of trading, and commerce, but the greateſt part of the Common-wealth be decayed alſo; for every man that lives by trading (being enforced to utter his com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modities in ſeverall parts, many times remote from his own habita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion) muſt of neceſſity undergo both trouble, and hazard in recover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing his juſt debts, it being impoſſible a Trade ſhould be continued without truſting; and there being no <hi>Attorneis</hi> that will remove from one Juriſdiction to another to attend the Cauſes there depending, the Creditor muſt be enforced, for want of an <hi>Attorney</hi> to proſecute his Action, to repair in perſon to the place, where he layes his Action, how remote ſoever it be from his own dwelling, and thither alſo bring his witneſſes at the hearing of his Cauſe, which, many times, through age, or other infirmities are unable to take ſo long a journey; and if the Debtor after judgement ſhall remove into another Juriſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diction, the proſecutor muſt go in perſon thither alſo, and there pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed upon that judgement; but if the Judges there ſhould not allow his former judgement, as, being ignorant of the grounds thereof, the proſecutor after his great expence, &amp; loſſe of time, would ſtill remain without remedie. 6ly, Trading decaying, there will likewiſe follow a generall fall in Rents in all places, and in all other commodities, ſo that all Tenants, which have taken Leaſes of lands, or houſes for any terme to come at a full Rent will alſo be undone; and though the State ſhould grant them liberty to reſigne their Leaſes, yet, that would not keep them long from poverty, although it might be ſome refreſhing for the preſent, there being no viſible means left them, to imploy the remainder of their ſtock for their ſubſiſtance; And not onely Tenants would be thus impoveriſhed, but all others much weakned in their Eſtates, and ſo unable to bear ſuch taxes, as ſhall neceſſarily be impoſed upon them for the ſupportation of the bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thens of the Common-wealth, or to relieve thoſe many Labourers, and Artificers, which would be brought to beggery, for want of work, and imployment, which might produce ſome ſad effects, and cauſe thoſe Labourers, and Artificers to take ſuch evill courſes, as may exceedingly diſturbe the peace, &amp; quiet of the Common-wealth: 7ly, Each ſeverall Juriſdiction would in time indeavour to become a Free State of themſelves, and deny dependance, or ſubordination un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to others, and refuſe, to joyn in counſell for the generall good of the Common-wealth, or give their common aſſiſtance in time of immi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:117850:3"/>danger ariſing in any other parts, unleſſe they may make their own conditions, whereby many miſchiefs and calamities will un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doubtedly follow, to the ruine of the Common wealth, the particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar members whereof being once disjoyned, the whole body will ſoon become a prey to the Enemy; theſe inconveniences are appa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent, many more will then diſcover themſelves, when it may be too late to ſeek a remedie.</p>
            <p n="2">2. That a ſevere courſe may be taken againſt the buying and ſel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling of Offices, and that the fees, and allowance of all Officers, Law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yers, and other Miniſters depending upon any Courts of Juſtice may be ſetled, and made known, And that no Office be impoſed upon a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny by compulſion, but that ſuch encouragement may be given to the undertakers of any Office, that they may willingly undergo the burthen thereof by having an allowance given them proportio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nable to the trouble, and charge incident to their reſpective Offices; For there is no reaſon that ſome ſhould be enricht by Offices of pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſit conferred upon them, whileſt others waſte themſelves, and their eſtates in the ſervice of the Common-wealth. And to the end the number of Offices may not be overburthenſome to the Common-wealth, a ſtrict inquiry may be made of the uſefulnes of all Offices, and ſuch continued only as ſhall be found uſefull for the ſervice of the Common-wealth, with ſuch a number of Officers as ſhall be ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſary for the managing thereof: that ſo the Common-wealth may not be overburthened with the multitude of ſuperfluous Offices, or Officers thereunto belonging, or the revenue thereof thereby exhau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſted. And, that for prevention of all abuſes committed by Bay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liffes choſen by the Shrief, the Conſtable in each Pariſh may be joy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned to execute all Writs, Warrants, and other proceſſe with liberty to break open any doors at ſeaſonable times, for the better executi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of ſuch Writs, and Warrants as ſhall be directed unto him, and that a ſevere penalty may be inflicted upon all that ſhall reſiſt him in the execution of his Office, or reſcue any apprehended by him, And that ſuch men may be put into that Office, as are known for their integrity, and may be reſponſable for thir actions. And that all Officers may be continued in their places, either during life, or ſo long as they diſcharge their ſeverall truths with faithfulneſſe, and none to be choſen annually, as heretofore, that by their long conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nuance in their Offices, they may the better know the duties of their places. And that the fees, and duty of all Officers may be publiſhed
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:117850:4"/>in Print, that their ſeverall powers and duties being made known unto all, they may be the better queſtioned for their injuſtice, or neglect; And that all Officers, or Miniſters depending upon any Courts of Juſtice, taking bribes or greater fees, or rewards then ſhall be allowed them by the appointment of the State, may be ſeverely puniſhed, and be for ever after held uncapable of any Office or pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick imployment in the Common-wealth.</p>
            <p n="3">3. That the Statute Laws, and other Laws may be well reviſed, and ſuch onely left in force, as ſhall be uſefull for the Common-wealth freed from the former niceties, and obſcurities; And that the benefit of all Fines, Iſſues, forfeitures of recognizances, &amp; all penalties, upon ſuch penall ſtatutes as upon the review ſhall be judged neceſſary to be continued, or hereafter to be enacted, may either be imployed, to the uſe of the reſpective parties dampnified, or ſo much thereof as may make them ſatisfaction for their loſſe ſuſtained thereby, or to the publick uſe of the County, where the offence ſhall be commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, with allowance of ſuch proportion thereof to the proſecutors, as ſhall be judged requiſite for their encouragement to diſcover thoſe offences, whereby the abuſe of Officers in eſtreating the ſaid Fines, or conniving thereat will be wholly taken away, and thoſe miſdemenours rectified, for which the ſaid fines, and penalties were impoſed, and the publick charge of the County thereby leſſned; And, to the end encouragement may be given for the apprehending of Robbers, and other felons, ſome allowance may be given to the apprehenders of them, proportionable to the quality of their offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, out of the goods, and eſtates of thoſe Robbers and felons, for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feited upon their attainders, and that part of the reſidue may be al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lotted to the looſer of his goods, in ſatisfaction of his loſſe, and the remainder, if any be) may be reſerved to defray the publick charge of the County, where the offence ſhall be committed, or the party apprehended.</p>
            <p n="4">4. That no perſons goods, or other eſtate may be exempted from the paiment of their debts, and that Commiſſioners in each County from time to time, be authorized to ſell the eſtates of ſuch debtors, as ſhall refuſe to ſatisfie their creditors within convenient time ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed by the ſaid Commiſſioners, rendring to the debtor the over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plus, that ſhall ariſe upon the ſale of his eſtate, after ſatisfaction gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven to the ſeverall creditors, and to alott to each creditor his juſt proportion where the eſtate is not ſufficient to ſatisfie them all; And
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:117850:4"/>that the ſaid Commiſſioners may be impowred to examine the ſaid debtors upon Oath, what ſums of money they owe, and to whom; and to examine all others upon Oath concerning the debtors eſtate, and that a ſevere penalty may be inflicted upon the concealors ther<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, to be imploied towards the further ſatisfaction of the creditors.</p>
            <p n="5">5. That care be taken for prevention of abuſes daily committed by guardians, and ſuch as are truſted with the managing of the e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtates of Infants, and that no married woman may be guardian to any, in regard ſhe being under the power of another cannot improve the eſtate of the Infant to the beſt advantage, but muſt ſubmit both the managing of the eſtate, and marriage of the Infant to the will of her husband, who often ſtrives to raiſe his fortune by the Infants ruine And that all guardians may give ſecurity to be accomptable for the profits of the Infants Lands, and may be liable to accompt to ſome friends of the Infants in the next degree, or to ſuch as ſhall be thereunto appointed by Authority, either every yeer, or as often as thoſe appointed to take the ſaid Accompt ſhall finde conve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nient; for tis impoſſible that the Infant when he comes of age ſhould have a cleere accompt of all the profits of his Lands received by his Guardian during his minority, or diſcover what hath been disbur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed for him during all that time, but muſt either take his Guardians word, or els exhibute a Bill for the diſcovery thereof, which often proves a fruitleſſe remedy, And that Guardians may be allowed du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring the minority of the Infant out of the revenew of his eſtate, to pay theſe debts the Infant ſhall be liable to pay when he comes to age, or his eſtate ſtand charged withall, whereby creditors may be relieved, which otherwiſe muſt ſtay, to their exceeding prejudice un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>till the Infant comes to age, And that executors may give ſecurity to perform the Will of the teſtator, and Adminiſtrators to give ſecurity for the paiment of the debts of the inteſtate, and for the equall diſtri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bution of the remainder of the goods to all that have right therto ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to Law: And that exemplifications of Wills, legally proved under the Seal of the Office, may be allowed in evidence upon trials for Land, aſwell as the Originall Will; And that all proviſoes, or conditions in Wills, or deeds may be adjudged void in Law, which ſhall reſtraine any perſons under any penalty, or upon the forfeiture of any Lands or goods ſetled upon them, from ſuing for any other Lands or goods ſetled upon any other perſons, by the ſaid Wills, or Deeds, or by any other, or from endevouring to overthrow the vali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dity
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:117850:5"/>of the ſaid Wils, or Deeds; that ſo all perſons may have free li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berty to recover their juſt rights, without hazarding any part there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, for by means of ſuch proviſoes, and conditions, many Heirs are diſ-inherited of great eſtates, and dare not ſue for any part thereof for fear of looſing all, or indevour to overthrow ſuch Wils, or Deeds, whereby that eſtate is ſetled upon others, who, working upon the weakneſs of the owners of ſuch eſtates, when they are not of perfect, and diſpoſing memory, do procure ſuch proviſoes, and conditions to be inſerted, which may ſecure their broken titles, and prevent all fu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture claims.</p>
            <p n="6">6. That, for the prevention of the daily miſ-imployment of lands, and money given to Hoſpitals, Colledges, and Schools, and to other charitable uſes, Commiſſioners may be ſetled in each County, for the calling to an account of all Governors of Hoſpitals, Colledges, and Schools, and of all other Feoffees in truſt for charitable uſes, how they have imployed the ſaid Lands, or money committed to their truſt, that ſo there may be a clear diſcovery of all abuſes there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in, and thoſe abuſes rectified, and the offendors puniſhed; And that the chargeable feaſts daily made by ſuch Governors, and Feoffees may be diſcontinued, and the expenſes thereof converted to a better uſe; And that ſpeciall care may be taken for the erecting of Schools in places convenient, and for the admitting to Scholerſhips, and Fel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowſhips, in the firſt place the children of the poorer ſort, whoſe in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>genuities ſhall make them capable thereof; And that the yearly al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowance of the govenours of Hoſpitalls, and Colledges may be ſo moderated, that they may not exceed in wealth by the poores reve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nues, and that the ſurpluſage of their revenues, may either be im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed for increaſing the number of the Poor, or Scollers in the reſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pective Hoſpitalls, and Colledges, or augmenting their allowance, where they have not ſufficient maintenance; or for the erecting of free Schools in places convenient, for the fitting of Schollers, to ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ply the vacancies in the reſpective Colledges thoſe Schooles ſhall be appropriated unto; And that a ſevere courſe may be taken againſt the buying and ſelling of Scholerſhips, and Fellowſhips, by inflicting pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalties, upon both buyers, and ſellors thereof.</p>
            <p n="7">7. That Tithes, which are found by ſad experience to be oppre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſſive to many people may be taken away, and care taken for the ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfaction of ſuch impropriators, at a generall charge, and that a ſtrict inquiry may be made therein, for many are uſurpt by ſeverall
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:117850:5"/>patrons, without any colour of a title to them, and that ſome other unoppreſſive way may be appointed for the maintenance of a faith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full Miniſtry in ſome meaſure ſuitable to their deſerts, and the great<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſe of the charge they undertake; And that each Congregation may be reſtored to the election of their Miniſters, with certain rules and cautions preſcribed for the more orderly proceedings therein, and for the caſting out of ſuch, as ſhall be ſcandalous, and unfit for the work of the Miniſtry.</p>
            <p n="8">8. That care be taken for the ballancing of Trade with forreign States, and making the Coin here currant equall in allay, and value with the Coine of other States, that this Common-wealth may not be impoveriſhed by forreign Merchants gaining the Trade, and by the tranſportation of Coine; And that forreign Nations may be pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hibited the fiſhing upon the Engliſh Coaſt, that ſo the people of this Land might reap the profit thereof unto themſelves, and not be for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ced to buy their own Fiſh of forreiners; And that cuſtomes may either be moderated or taken away, unles it may be a policy in State to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinue the paiment of cuſtomes upon all commodities brought in by forreign Merchants; for if the yearly income accrewing to the State by cuſtomes, ſhould be compared to the vaſt ſums, the people pay by the exchantment of the price of all commodities paſſing through many hands before they come to be made uſe of, the diſproportion would ſeem almoſt incredible, for every Trader looks to gaine, aſwel, by the ſum he paies for Cuſtome, as by the ſum he firſt disburſed for the commodity, which carries with it an increaſe of gaine through every hand it paſſeth, ſo that the people who are neceſſita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted to make uſe of thoſe commodities, pay much more then comes in cleerly to the State, beſides the ſums expended, in collecting of it in Fees to the ſeverall Officers imployed therein; for remedying of which inconvenience, and leſſning of the peoples burthens ſuch a courſe may be taken that all monies to be raiſed for the publick uſe, may be leavied by an equall rate proportionally to mens reall and perſonall eſtate, without exemption of any Land from the paiment of its due proportion, if the people would conſider the benefit they ſhould reap thereby, and therewith reſt contented, untill the great affaires of the Common-wealth would permit a relaxation of thoſe taxes, which are the eaſier to be born in regard they are brought, in at a certaine, and cheap rate, and the collectors thereof more ſubject to a ſtrict accompt.</p>
            <pb n="8" facs="tcp:117850:6"/>
            <p n="9">9. That care be taken for the encouragement and encreaſe of Trade throughout the Common-wealth, by prohibiting the tranſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portation of ſuch commodities, which may any waies prejudice the manufactures of this Land; that ſo there may be imployment in pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fitable Trades for all thoſe that being willing to work, are now ready to periſh for want of work and imployment, And for the avoiding the many miſdemenours committed daily by perſons of diſſolute life and converſation, care to be taken for the compelling ſuch to work, and puniſhing thoſe that ſhall refuſe, and ſpend their time, and eſtates in Innes, and Alhouſes, for prevention of which inconveni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ences, the licenſing and ſuppreſſing of Taverns, Innes, and Alehouſes may be referred to the diſcretion of the Juſtices of peace in the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verall Limits, whereby, the number of ſuch houſes being leſſned, thoſe that continue, may the better maintain themſelves without diſorder; And that ſome ſtricter courſe may be taken, for the freeing this Land from that curſed crew of Rogues, and Vagabonds, which ſpend aſmuch, or more then would maintain the poore, and renders this Land the ſcorn and deriſion of other Nations, who might more profitably be ſet on work at home, or being incorrigeable, tranſpor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted into other plantations abroad; And, that the number of labou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rers may not encreaſe beyond the portion of work that may conve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niently be provided for them, care be taken for the prohibiting the building new cottages in Burroughs, and Market Townes without laying ſome conſiderable portion of Land thereunto; and that no new Cottage may be erected out of Market Towns without laying thereunto a double portion of Land required by the ſtatute, and the like portion of Land to be laid to all Cottages already built, where the owner of ſuch Cottage hath ſufficient Land in the ſame Pariſh to make up that proportion; for where Cottages depend wholly upon their labour, and have neither Corn, not Cattell to ſupply wants through ſikneſſe, or other caſualties, they ſoon are brought to po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verty; And whereas the owners of Cottages, by the exceſſive rents reſerved upon them, do often cauſe their Tenants to be chargeable to the reſpective Pariſhes where they live, ſuch care may be taken therein that the Landlords may be compelled to allow ſuch a pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portion of their Rents to their decaied, and impoveriſht Tenants as may free the Pariſh from the burthen of maintaining them.</p>
            <p n="10">10. That confederation may be taken of the ſufferings of Coppy holders by the exceſſive fines, and Heriots taken at every change ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:117850:6"/>to the will of the ſeverall Lords, which coppyholders are often alſo enforced by the exactions of their Lords, to renew their eſtates for yeares inſtead of lives, which Leaſes once expired, their coppyhold eſtate is quite extinct, and ſo thoſe Lands become whol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly at the Lords diſpoſe; The condition alſo of the ſeverall Tenants to corporations, and companies in Cities, and Burroughs is grown of late as miſerable as the other, whoſe Tenants having eſtates for lives, or yeares have expended large ſums of money in building, and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther improvements of the Land they held, in hope of having their e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtates renewed at the uſuall rates upon the expiration of their ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rall termes, but of late ſuch exceſſive Fines have bin impoſed upon them, that they have been uncapable of renewing their eſtates, and ſo have been compelled to leave thoſe Lands which they and their pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deceſſors have enjoyed for many yeares to be poſſeſt by ſome of the alliance, or dependants of their Landlords, without any ſatisfaction had for their disburſements and improvements, the Fines ſo taken ſeldome being imployed to any other uſe but the feaſting of them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, and others, the yearly rents, and profits of thoſe Lands being ſufficient to diſcharge the ſeverall uſes thoſe Lands were firſt apoin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted for, without the taking ſuch exceſſive Fines, And further that ſuch a courſe may be taken, that all other Tenants alſo (who by their own particular charge, and induſtry ſhall much improve the Lands they hold, may have reaſonable ſatisfaction made them by their Landlords, in caſe they ſhall not reap the benefit of their improve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment before the expiration of their Leaſes; that ſo they may the bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter be encouraged to improve the Lands they hold to the beſt advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage of the Common-wealth, without receiving any prejudice by ſuch improvements.</p>
            <p n="11">11. That conſideration may be taken of the large, and vaſt circu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>its of ground lying waſte, and in great meaſure unprofitable, and ſome courſe taken for the improvement thereof for the benefit of thoſe that are intereſted therein, according to their ſeverall inte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſts, and proportions. And that, where the commoners, or owners of ſuch grounds refuſe to make an improvement thereof themſelves, li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berty may be given to any others to improve thoſe waſts, allowing ſuch reaſonable ſatisfaction to the proprietors, as ſhall be thought fit, by ſuch Commiſſioners as ſhall be appointed for that purpoſe, and for the deciding of all other differences that ſhall ariſe amongſt the improvers; and that liberty may be given to the owners of all other
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:117850:7"/>Lands to improve the ſame, where the advantage to the Common-wealth by ſuch improvement may out ballance particular intereſts, and advantages, and no depopulation thereupon enſue; and to the end the poorer ſort of people may enjoy the benefit of ſuch com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons as ſhall be thought fit to be continued, aſwell as others who have greater ſtocks, all right of commoning without number may be taken away, and every commoner allowed his due proportion, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the proportion of his Lands; And that for the avoiding many ſuits in Law, each Pariſh may enjoy the commons therein unto them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, and no others not having any Lands therein, to be entercom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moners with them, either by preſcription, or by any other title; And that encouragement may be given for the more diligent ſearching after mines of all ſorts by permitting the owners of the ground, where any mine of any metal ſhall be found, to reap the ſole benefit thereof without any ſeiſure by the State, as heretofore.</p>
            <p n="12">12. That a ſtrict inquiry may be made by Commiſſioners in every County of all generall nuſances, erecting of Mills, planting of War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rens, turning of water courſes, or Highwaies, or the like, or of any thing els that may be more prejudiciall to the borderers, then either advantageous to the party or the Common-wealth, and ſuch of them rectified or taken away that ſhall be ſo found; And to the end all Highwaies leading to Market Towns may be made more paſſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble, all perſons may be compellable under a certain penalty to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paire thoſe wayes as far as his own Land lieth, with the like liberty for the gathering of ſtones, or digging ſtones, or gravell in any mans Land within the ſame Pariſh as formerly was given to the Pariſh by the ſtatute, and where the highway lies between two perſons ground both of them to joine in the charge of the repairing of it, as far as their Land lieth, in that manner, for commonly ſuch waies are made defective by the meanes of thoſe that border thereupon, and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the more fit to be repaired by them, rather then by ſuch poor people, who are not able to ſupport themſelves, and Families du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring the time required by the ſtatutes now in force, for their aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance, and that thoſe Highwaies as lie through waſts, and commons, may be repaired by the Commoners, and Lord of the Soil, where his profit out of the ſaid waſts, and Commons is conſiderable, by ſuch proportions as ſhall be reaſonable, and where the owner of Land ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joyning to the way, is not able through povertie to repaire his part, that defect either so be ſupplied by the Pariſh, or by ſuch therein, as
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:117850:7"/>have no Land adjoining to thoſe Highwaies; that ſo the burthen may be born with moſt equality.</p>
            <p n="13">13. That all Faires may be kept upon certain daies of the month, and not according to the former moveable Feaſts; for thoſe daies will never be forgotten by the people, ſo long as they continue to be a guide for any buſines, and that after a generall ſettlement of all Faires, a catalogue thereof may be ſet forth in Print, that all may have ſufficient notice of the alterations; And that for the better pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vention of the frequent ſtealing of Horſes, a ſtrict courſe may be ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken, that no Horſe may be ſold in Faire, or Market without being entred into the Toll Book, with the names of the buyer, ſeller, and voucher, and of the place of their ſeverall reſidencies, and that the keeper of the toll Book enter no Horſe therein, unleſſe the ſeller, or voucher be known unto him, upon paine of making ſatisfaction for the Horſe to the owner that hath loſt him; and that the voucher not knowing the ſeller and his place of reſidence may undergo the like penalty; and that an Office may be erected in <hi>London,</hi> into which all keepers of toll Books ſhall certifie all horſes entred into their ſeverall Toll Books, with their particular marks, and prizes, with the names of the buyer, ſeller, and voucher, and of the places of their ſeverall reſidencies, within one month afrer the entrance of them, that being recorded in the ſaid Office all looſers of Horſes may repaire thither, and be informed where their Horſes were ſold, and the ſtealer there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by diſcovered; And that ſome fitting allowance may be given to the keeper of the ſaid Office; and ſome additionall allowance given to the keeper of the toll Book by the buyer and ſeller of the Horſe, if it ſhall be thought requiſite in reſpect of his trouble in certifying the ſale thereof into the ſaid Office.</p>
            <p n="14">14. That none by vertue of any tenure, grant, charter, Office, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gree, or place of reſidence, may be exempted from the ordinary courſe of Law, but that the ſame juſtice may be equally adminiſtred unto al; And that all privileges heretofore granted to any perſons, or to any corporations, or companies in Cities, or Burroughs may be ſeriouſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly conſidered, and ſuch of them made void, as ſhall be found unreſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nable, or oppreſſive to the people, And that all perſons reſident in Corporations, and Burrough Towns, may have liberty to appeal to the Judges of Aſſize, or Juſtices at the generall Quarter-ſeſſions, upon any unjuſt proceedings againſt them by the Juſtices of the ſaid cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>porations, or Burrough-towns otherwiſe Juſtices in corporations
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:117850:8"/>being either ignorant of the Laws, or led by private intereſts, may do injuſtice without controul, who are Juſticss onely by their Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, and not by Commiſſion.</p>
            <p n="15">15. That ſome titles of Honour may be conferred upon the emi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent maintainers of the Liberties of the Common-wealth, anſwera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble to the greatneſſe of their ſervices they have performed; for there is no reaſon, that ſuch as have been enemies to the Common-wealth and Liberties thereof ſhould enjoy their titles of Honour, whilſt thoſe that have ſubdued them, and ſo often hazarded their lives for the ſervice of the Common-wealth ſhould ſtill remain as private men, without any notice taken of their deſerts; And further it may be conſidered, whether it may not be more advantageous to the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon-wealth, and add more to the reputation of all thoſe that ſhall be honoured with ſuch titles, That all titles of Honour may conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nue but for life, and not be made hereditary unles the ſucceſſor inhe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riting the vertues of his predeceſſor ſhall be thought worthy by the State, to have the ſame honours conferred upon him, which courſe may cauſe ſuch perſons to endeavour to exceed their Predeceſſors in their vertues, and engagements to the State, and be a means that honours may be lookt upon as badges of deſert, and not be ſtained by the diſſolute, and unworthy carriage of any, as hath been too of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten ſeen; And further it may be conſidered, whether it may not be convenient, and for the ſervice of the Common-wealth, rather to caſt an eye of favour upon ſuch perſons, who having formerly oppo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed the State, ſhall now ſhew an evident demonſtration of their true converſion, by the acknowledgment of their former errors, and cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diall ſubmiſſion to the preſent Government, then ſtill to let ſuch per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, eminent for their parts and ingenuities, to live like drones in a Common-wealth, uncapable of imployment, whoſe future ſervices might countervaile their former errors, and heal the breaches made amongſt us, by a former union.</p>
            <p n="16">16. That for the better holding correſpondency with forreign States, and managing the weighty buſines of the Common-wealth with greater ſafety, the Members of the Councell of State may be continued, ſo long as they discharge their truſt with faithfulnes, and not be ſubject to a yearly change; for a ſucceſſion of perſons of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten changed cannot mannage the weighty affaires committed to their truſt, with that advantage and ſecurity to the Common-wealth or ſo eaſily diſcover the ſecret ſtratagems contrived by Forreign
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:117850:8"/>States, or ſo well fruſtrate their devices, often long in hatching as thoſe, that by their long experience in affairs of State, and by their holding of intelligence in Forreign Princes Courts, do obſerve the growth of ſuch deſignes, whereby they may prevent the evills that would follow, and carry on the grand concernments of the State with greater ſafety; for no man's born a Statesman, And if a yearly change of Councellors, as ſome deſire ſhould be admitted by the State, what encouragement would any have to waſte their time, and treaſure to fit them ſelves for that imployment, which would laſt but ſo ſhort a time? and what miſchiefes would attend the State, which would be ſwaied by raw, and ignorant Stateſmen? for in King <hi>James</hi> his time, it was obſerved, that when the ancient ſtock of grave, and prudent Councellours was decaied, and others placed in their roomes, not having that experience in the affairs of State, the honour of this Nation was exceedingly impaired, and ſome forreign States gained thoſe advantages ſo prejudiciall to this Nation, that to this day could never be regained.</p>
            <p n="17">17. That to prevent the many inconveniences that may ariſe by the often change of perſons in authority, ſecure proviſion may be made, from the diſſolution of this preſent Parliament, for the e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quall diſtribution of elections in all Counties, with certain rules and cautions preſcribed for the more orderly proceeding at elections; and for making diſaffected perſons uncapable of being elected, or electors or being preſent at elections; and that none under a ſevere penalty ſhall give any reward, or other recompence to any perſon for his vote at any election, or before, or after; And that none but freehol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders of ſuch a yearly value, as ſhall be judged fit, may have a vote at any election, and all tenants, and Coppyholders to continue ſtill diſabled, to elect, or to be preſent at elections; for ſhould all Tenants any coppyholders (who depend upon the will of their Landlords and other Lords of mannours) be allowed to give their votes at ſuch elections, many diſaffected perſons (which ſhould be thought fit to be diſabled themſelves to vote at ſuch elections) inſtead of their own ſingle votes, would procure many to vote according to their own defires; whereby many diſaffected perſons would become mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers of the ſupreme Councell of the Common-wealth, and ſo the Common-wealth betraied; And, that the continuance of each Parli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ament may be left to the wiſdom of the particular members thereof, that ſo they may have time for the diſpatch of the great affairs com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:117850:9"/>to their care, and for the remedying of the grievances of the Common-wealth; for tis impoſſible to predict what weighty buſines may befall each Parliament, and what obſtructions they may meet withall in the diſpatch thereof; what rules can then exactly be pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribed unto them for the time of their continuance or had this pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Parliament been either limited a certain period, or tied to the exact performance of ſuch rules, as ſhould have been preſcribed unto them by any former Parliaments; inſtead of that happy peace, and liberty is enjoyed, this Common-wealth had been involved in per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>petuall ſlavery.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
